Frederick K. Articuno

Portfolio - fkarticuno.github.io/CodingPortfolio LinkedIn - linkedin.com/in/frederick-articuno

Github - github.com/fkarticuno

Email - mckiyoshi@gmail.com Phone - 804-704-0334

Location - Colonial Heights, Virginia 23834

Summary

Full-Stack Web Developer leveraging over 10 years of development across numerous frameworks and languages. Known as a curious mind with a continuous focus on the next steps and perpetual improvement. With each project, the goal is to use current knowledge to develop a stable platform from which to expand from the minimum viable product into the frontiers of technology. Excited to leverage skills in the future as part of a fast-paced, quality-driven team in order to build better experiences on the web and develop more concise code for the future.

Technical Skills

JavaScript | JQuery | CSS | HTML | Firebase | NodeJS | Git | CSS | Bootstrap | JavaScript | JQuery | Timers | Ajax Firebase | JS-Constructors | MySQL | Express | Handlebars | Sequelize | MongoDB

Projects

Having applied aspects of UX, UI, and agile development during projects working in a team of four to develop an app aimed at consumers interested in finding brick and mortar resources ranging from nearby schools, restaurants, housing, and more.

Coding Portfolio / https://fkarticuno.github.io/CodingPortfolio/

Portfolio displaying progress and achievements developing basic, intermediate and advanced apps using various languages, packages, frameworks, engines and database models. All culminating into a demo friendly environment to showcase the expertise gained through countless hours of development and refactoring.

Uses: HTML CSS Bootstrap JavaScript JQuery GitHub-Pages

Drinking Well / https://sheltered-spire-36283.herokuapp.com/

This databasing app keeps track of a users favorite mixed drinks, allowing them to learn about mixology, and try new things by giving them recipes for random or user selected beverages. This app, hosted by heroku, leverages express and node.js to provide server and routing, mysql for databasing, passport.js for authentication while making calls to a robust beverage API to return drink names, images, ingredients, measurements, and instructions along with a second API call to YouTube to provide an instructional video.

Uses: Bootstrap HTML CSS JQuery JavaScript MySQL Heroku Express Sequelize

Eat-Da-Burger / https://eat-da-burger-fka.herokuapp.com/

A restaurant style app that lets users input the names of burgers they would like to eat, when submitted the app will store the burger in its database, compile a JSON variant, and reproduce the updated list of burgers. While in the 'waiting area' burgers have buttons to trigger CSS changes on favorite and to devour (delete) the selected burger. The app will however store all burgers added in a separate table permanently.

Uses: CSS Bootstrap HTML JavaScript MySQL Sequelize JQuery

Work Experience

Capital One Chester, Virginia

Sr. Risk coordinator 02/2017 –

05/2019

Manage inbound/outbound calls to service accounts.

Risk coordinator 02/2016 – 02/2017

Received 4 ROAR awards for performing at top 5%.

Sr. Risk representative 08/2015 – 02/2016

Help customers build and retain strong credit standing.

AmeriCorps Petersburg, Virginia 08/2012 – 05/2013

Volunteer

Developed leadership, vocational education, and construction skills in Youth Build Students.

<u>United States Marine Corps</u> [Secret clearance] Virginia Beach, Virginia 08/2009 – 8/2017

Data Link Coordinator - E5 Sergeant

Developed and maintained network topology.

System Configuration Coordinator - E4 Corporal

Sourced and maintained interoperability equipment.

Tactical Air Traffic Controller - E4 Corporal

Managed Air traffic in/out of designated AORs

Assistant Controller - E3 - Lance Corporal

Assisted controllers with time sensitive info flow.

Surveillance Operator - E2 PFC

Maintained identification of all RADAR correlations.

Education

Full Stack Coding Certification - University Of Richmond

Capital One Tech College - John Tyler Community College

Marine Corps Air Ground Combat Center - Tidewater Community College